worldfirst.com 2014-09-25

# Privacy policy

At World First we pride ourselves on offering the highest levels of security, transparency and integrity when it comes to protecting our clients' interests.

That's why World First UK Ltd ("World First UK") and World First Markets Ltd ("World First Markets") are both registered as Data Controllers with the Information Commission Office.  To make sure, please feel free to check our registration [here](http://www.ico.org.uk/esdwebpages/search/).

World First UK and World First Markets are part of the World First Group companies ("the Group") which also includes World First USA, Inc. (based in the USA) and World First Pty Ltd (based in Australia).

This policy applies to information that the World First Group may collect about visitors to our website, companies and individuals who register for our services and continue to make use of our services and any other person who corresponds with us over the phone or in writing.

Our aim is to give you reassurance that any personal information will be used fairly and only for the purposes for which it was collected.

Please review this Privacy Policy prior to registering an account and providing us with your personal information.  Client confidentiality is our main concern and through good practices we strive to ensure that:

  * only information which is necessary for adherence to the regulations and/or improvement of our service is collected;
  * personal information is collected fairly; and
  * personal information is stored securely.

The Data Protection Act 1998 ("DPA") regulates the collection, processing and storing or personal data.  When your information is processed by a data controller you are referred to as a data subject. 

If you have any further questions about data protection with World First, please don't hestiate to get in touch with your dedicated dealer and we will do our level best to alleviate any of your concerns. 

## We use your information for the following purposes:

## How do we collect information about you?

World First collects information about you when you visit our website, register for an account (whether online or by completing our paper based forms) or when you correspond with us over the phone or in writing. 

When you register for an account with us we collect, process and store information including but not limited to, your name, postal address, email address, telephone numbers, date of birth. Once your account is fully set up and you begin to transact with us we will collect, process and store financial and transactional information.

We also use Cookies to improve your experience when visiting our website. This is discussed in further detail below.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers downloaded on to a device when the user accesses certain websites. A cookie will allow a website to recognise a user’s device.

A cookie will contain the name of internet location (the domain) from which the cookie has come and the lifetime of the cookie (a cookie will usually expire after a certain period of time).

Two types of cookies are used on this website:

  * Session cookies which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site and;
  * Persistent cookies which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie).

How we use cookies on our site and what information we collect:

## Session cookies

We use session cookies:

To allow you to carry information across pages of our site and avoid having to re-enter information.

## Persistent cookie

We use persistent cookies:

    * We may use persistent cookies from time to time to help us recognise you as a unique visitor when you return to our website and to monitor your use of our website;
    * To allow us to link you to any of our Partners of Affiliates should you come to our website through a paid advert or banner on a website of an Affiliate or Partner.

## Use of web beacons

Some of our web pages may contain web beacons which allow us to count users who have visited these pages. Web beacons collect only limited information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the web beacon resides. These beacons do not carry any personally identifiable information and are used to track the effectiveness of a particular marketing campaign.

## What do we use your information for?

The law says that personal information shall be obtained, used and disclosed fairly. We use your personal information to allow us to process your registration, process any transactions you may book through us and to maintain the accuracy of information on your account.

**Registration and administration**

We use your information to enable you to register with us. Once you have an account with us we will use your details to contact you and to reply to any queries or requests. We may use your information in the administration of your account, which includes us contacting you in order to update your account details (this assists us with keeping our records as up to date as possible) or in order to notify you of changes or improvements to our products or services that may affect our service to you.

**Our products and services**

We use your information in order to supply our products and services to you and to meet our contractual obligations to you. Additionally we may need to notify you of any changes relating to our products and services.

**Prevention and detection of crime**

World First is subject to strict anti-money laundering regulations which requires us to undertake due diligence on our customers. This may include the use of electronic verification tools.  Where electronic verification is not possible we will require copies of identification documents and proof of address.  

We may need to pass your information on to Governmental departments, regulatory bodies (including HM Revenue and Customs or the FCA), the police/law enforcement agencies or to a court of law. This would be done, for example, to assist in the prevention of a crime (money laundering/fraud), to meet legal requirements or for other lawful purposes.

**Marketing**

We may use your information to keep you up to date concerning our products and services. 

Client surveys help us to improve our services. We may send you emails inviting you to participate in surveys or asking for feedback on our services. The information may be shared with affiliated third parties in aggregate form only. 

We may market our services to you through social media platforms using information you provide to us when you interact on our website or sign up for our services. We may pass this information onto our third parties such as Facebook, for this purpose. Please contact us if you do not want to receive these sorts of adverts by emailing [marketing@worldfirst.com](mailto:marketing@worldfirst.com).

**Monitoring**

We record all our telephone calls for security and training purposes.

## Information security / storage

We have physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that protect your information. We store all data electronically. Data is stored on servers located in the UK and which are protected by actively maintained firewalls. We make use of up-to-date anti-virus software and the servers have restricted physical access. 

If you provide paper based documentation we may retain the paper documents in addition to saving copies in an electronic format. 

Transmission of data on the internet can never be completely secure. We do not and cannot guarantee security of information collected or transmitted electronically however, we take reasonable care to safeguard your personal information. 

## Data sharing

**World First Group Companies**

We may share your information with other companies in the World First Group in order to provide you with access to our services. While certain Group companies are based outside of the EEA we ensure that data protection requirements are consistent across the Group.   

**Regulators**  

We may need to share your information with regulators such as the Financial Conduct Authority, HMRC or law enforcement agencies. 

**Banks**

We may need to share your information with with third parties in order to process your transactions e.g. our banking counterparties

Additionally owing to the nature of our business we may need to share your information with people or organisations outside of the EEA such as intermediary or beneficiary banks e.g. you request us to make a USD payment to China the funds would be cleared through an intermediary bank in the US before reaching China. We are required to include certain information on the payment which may include your name and address.

**Other parties**

We may share your information with anyone that you have given us permission to, any person acting on your behalf or with a co-branded World First partner who may have introduced you to us. 

We may share your information with trusted companies providing services to us under confidentiality agreements or to companies that assist us in providing our services to you e.g. card transaction processing. These companies do not have any rights to share your information with other third parties (unless required by law) or to market other services to you.

We do not sell any personal data that we hold about you.

## How do I request information?

You have the right to request details of the information we hold about you, a description of that data, the purposes for which it is being used and any parties with which we share your information. 

We may charge you an administration fee for providing this information. Your request should be made in writing to the Data Protection Officer at legal.desk@worldfirst.com for further information.

## How long is personal information retained?

World First will only retain your information for as long as is necessary but usually no more than 6 years after the end of the business relationship.

## How is this policy updated?

We may amend this policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes to the way we use your personal information we will notify you by posting a prominent notice on our website.
